# **MASSIMINO Pascal**

Compression - Image & Media processing - Large-Scale Engineering

C++, assembly (NEON, x86), GLSL, and anything around to make these work and shipped at scale.

Deep hands-on 'get things done' engineering, along with a researcher mindset. Hardware and software.

pascal.massimino@gmail.com cell: +33 6 51 92 05 90 - Paris Area - <a href="https://skal65535.github.io">https://skal65535.github.io</a>

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Google** — Principal Engineer

2006 - PRESENT:

- <u>Streetview</u>: imagery, backend, serving, <u>jpeg compression</u> (used everywhere at Google)
- YouTube: back-end, video compression, thumbnails, processing pipeline, Video for VR
- WebP: initiator of the format, wrote most of the initial code, worked with the ecosystem on adoption and user support.
  - Public talks to influencers: 2020 WebP Rewind, 2021 WebP Recap
  - WebP2: Next-gen format my team and I experimented with.
  - Researched compressing images in ~200 bytes
- <u>AOMedia</u>: developing <u>AV1/AVIF</u> video codec with industry partners.
  - Public advocate and speakers: #1 in french, #2, #3, slides, ...
- Manager of small dedicated team
- 21 US patents

## **XviD Solutions GmbH** — Co-Founder

2000 - 2007, Video Codec Consulting & Development

Co-Founded Xvid Solutions to leverage the open-source development of the XviD code (in Ffmpeg notably).

Wrote MPEG2, H263, H264 codecs for various DSP platforms in all sorts of low-level languages.

Shipped in volume to numerous set-top boxes and home devices.

## **Ilog**, Paris — Senior Engineer

2000–2005, Operation Research and Constraint Propagation technology. Worked on the flagship Scheduler product until the acquisition by IBM.

## **EDUCATION and RESEARCH**

## **PhD**, **1999** — Theoretical Physics

- Elastic Ising Models : <u>Modèle d'Ising compressible</u> (in french)
- Effect of magnetoelastic interactions on the phase transition of two-dimensional Ising spin system

Alma mater: Ecole Normale Superieure de Paris (1991)

#### **SIDE INTERESTS**

- FinTech: business angel and investor, notably for <u>Kard</u>
- Entrepreneur / consulting: metaskal.com
- Marathon & Trail runner Rock Climbing Muay Thai Music & Rock band